=Love Story in the 1970s=
=Episode 18=
What's wrong?
Feeling unwell?
Fei Ting.
I'm telling you.
I don't care
whether you like this job or not.
Fei Ni spent a lot of effort
to get you this job.
It's not just about you.
You might just affect
Fei Ni's relationship with Ms. Wang.
It can't be that serious.
What do you know?
You need to listen to me.
Don't come here anymore.
Even if you loathe this job,
you're staying forever
in the Publicity Division,
got it?
Fei Ting.
I don't ask much from you.
I just want us to live
a simple live together.
Do you know how happy I was
when you got this job?
Everyone said I was so lucky.
When I returned home,
even my sister-in-law
stopped looking down on me.
But you?
Instead of working hard,
you're being stubborn.
Can't you spare a thought for me?
Why are you crying?
Stop crying.
People would think
I did something to you.
I was wrong.
I promise you,
I won't come here anymore.
You better mean what you say.
It's a deal.
Take this.
(Mixed Fruit Candies)
Share it with your boss and colleagues.
We didn't offer any wedding favors.
They might talk bad behind you.
I'm off, then.
Go back and work.
Take that apron off.
Go to work.
Did she cry or not?
(Duty Room)
Hello.
Who are you looking for?
I'm looking for Dr. Qu Hua.
Dr. Qu?
He's in operation.
Who's on the line?
Should I leave a message for him?
No, thank you.
(Comrade Qu Hua.)
(After much thought,)
(I believe it's better we divorce.)
(We married for mutual benefits,)
(and we've gotten what we wanted.)
(There's no need to stay
in this loveless marriage.)
(What do you think?)
(Please reply.)
(Divorce Agreement,
Initiated by: Fang Mujing)
Dr. Qu.
The operation hall is ready.
Okay, got it.
(Sender: Fang Mujing
To: Qu Hua)
My mom invited you over for dinner.
Why should I go to your home?
Why?
Because you're my girlfriend.
Really?
I thought you're just using me
as a tool to annoy Fei Ni.
Ling Yi.
You've got the wrong idea.
I did use you to annoy Fei Ni,
but you're not a tool.
You're a living, breathing human.
I just couldn't stand the sight
of Fei Ni and Fang Muyang together.
I was confused.
How is Fang Muyang
better than me in any way?
Ye Feng.
I think you're better than Fang Muyang
in every way,
but I don't understand
why you're comparing yourself to him.
You think I'm better than Fang Muyang
in every way?
Of course.
Your education, job,
your family,
your looks...
You're superior than him in every way.
Besides,
you're a great basketball player.
Why didn't Fei Ni choose me, then?
When I was working
in the production team,
there's a saying among the locals.
Fish attracts fish,
shrimps attract shrimps,
and turtles attract...
Turtles attract what?
Turtles attract tortoises.
I know it's vulgar,
but it makes sense.
Fei Ni didn't choose you
not because you're not good enough,
or because you're not
as good as Fang Muyang.
It's because...
She likes that tortoise.
Anyway,
I think you shouldn't
doubt yourself because of
a wrong choice made by someone else,
let alone...
Let alone use me.
Sorry, Ling Yi.
I was just annoyed by Fei Ni
and Fang Muyang.
You're right.
Fei Ni didn't choose me,
and that's her own problem.
She's got poor taste.
She...
Anyway,
I was wrong.
I shouldn't have focused on Fei Ni
and neglected your feelings.
Ling Yi.
From today onward,
let's forget
everything bad between us.
We'll make this work, okay?
We missed that movie last time.
I want to watch it.
Sure!
Let's catch a movie
and have dinner at my house!
Mom!
Lin Mei!
The Publicity Division
is visiting workers today,
and I've been asked to follow.
At least stay for dinner.
I'm in a rush.
That boy...
It's okay, Mom.
Work comes first.
I'll deliver his dinner later.
Besides,
if he's asked to follow,
it means Ms. Wang favors him.
It's a good thing.
You're right.
Eat more.
Ni.
Are you two dating for real?
You're not lying this time, are you?
Mom.
If you don't believe us,
we can kiss in front of you.
No!
I believe you.
Did they kiss?
I'm covering my eyes.
I can't see.
Can't you make a gap
between your fingers and peek?
They're kissing.
That's enough.
(Reception Room)
Hello, sir.
Who are you looking for?
I'm Fei Ting's wife.
He works at the Publicity Division.
I brought his dinner.
Publicity Department?
Everyone has left.
I thought they're visiting workers?
Why would they visit anyone
when there's no special occasion?
There's no such thing.
So, did Fei Ting come back?
No.
Thank you, sir.
Why are you still awake?
How many families did you visit?
Why are you back so late?
How many...
No, I...
I had some work to finish afterwards.
I went back to the factory.
I brought your dinner to the factory.
Why did the receptionist say
there's no such activity?
What would they know?
Why would we tell the Reception Room
about our work
in the Publicity Division?
Wait.
What's that smell?
Why do I smell
some snow cream on you?
Let me smell that.
The factory's workers
are using this cream,
right?
That's enough.
I'm pooped.
Go take a bath.
I'll skip.
No need.
No, take a bath.
Or else I won't let you sleep.
Be gentle.
Don't wake your parents up.
Why do I also
smell lard on his shirt?
(To: Fang Mujing)
Is that from your husband?
(From: Qu Hua)
What did he give you?
Probably nothing nice.
(Braised Beef)
(It's getting cold,)
(so I bought you a sweater.)
(I hope it fits.)
(I chose your favorite color.)
(You can share the milk candies)
(with your colleagues,)
(except Liu Wei.)
(Save the canned foods for yourself.)
(Jiangnan People's Hospital)
Dr. Qu.
A call for you.
Hello, I'm Qu Hua.
Have you been busy?
Manageable.
Did you receive my letter?
Yes.
Why didn't you reply?
I did.
Didn't you receive it?
Bye.
(Braised Beef)
Ding Yang.
Have some candies.
So many candies?
I'll just take two.
Take this, too.
For me?
Mujing.
Your husband is so nice to you.
(From: Qu Hua)
(Male Sweater)
This looks good.
It does.
It looks difficult to make, though.
Not at all.
Hey,
I can teach you.
If you can't make it,
I'll make one for you.
No.
I have to make it myself.
Doing it yourself?
Sure.
(Male Sweater)
This one looks simpler.
I'll make this, then.
Sure.
By the way,
what are
your husband's measurements?
His waist...
It's about the same as Mr. Chen's.
His shoulders are about
as wide as Mr. Xu's.
You're not very close
with your husband, are you?
Yang.
You can work here for now.
Thank you, Uncle Fu.
Remember.
Mr. Yuan's submissions
are our top priority.
Focus on that.
I've gathered
all the information you need.
Tell me
if you need anything.
Don't worry, Uncle Fu.
I'll complete my tasks.
I won't let you and Mr. Yuan down.
Okay, get to work.
(Document Folder)
Mr. Liao, here are
the documents you asked for.
Fang Muyang.
Have you finished training?
Yes.
So, you've been assigned to the press?
Not exactly.
I'm illustrating
for Mr. Yuan's work temporarily.
I'm interning as a reporter.
Come to me if you need anything.
Thanks.
But, I don't think
our work is related.
Keep a close eye on patient 17.
Inform me immediately
if he has a fever.
Okay.
Patient 26
can be discharged tomorrow
if everything's normal.
Okay, Dr. Qu.
Get to work.
(To: Qu Hua
From: Fang Mujing)
(It's getting cold.
Remember to bundle up.)
Qu Hua.
It's not even winter now.
Why are you all bundled up?
I have a slight cold.
That's why.
Need some cold medicine?
No.
It'll get better soon.
Dumplings are ready!
Come on.
Today is an occasion
of double happiness.
Now, we have
two new family members.
As the head
of this family...
I mean, occasionally.
I'd like to welcome Fang
and Lin Mei
to our big, warm family.
Come on.
Thank you.
Cheers.
Take it easy.
You don't want to pass out.
I'm fine.
I seldom drink
because of you.
Listen, Fang.
When it comes to drinking,
no one can beat me.
Come on.
As for me,
I don't ask for much.
I just hope that my children
can enjoy
a prosperous
and peaceful new year.
Better yet, you should have children.
We can babysit for you
while we're still healthy.
Mom, don't worry.
We'll do our best.
Yeah.
Nice!
Yes.
Do your best.
Yeah.
What about you?
We will.
Dig in.
Let's try the dumplings.
Cheers to you.
Try the dumplings.
They'll turn cold soon.
Lin Mei.
Wait.
Here.
Before we dig in,
I have something to say.
Mom.
We're at home,
not the factory.
Now...
Let her say.
Fine.
Ling Yi.
You've been dating
Ye Feng for quite some time.
Your parents aren't around,
so I'd like
to make a suggestion.
After the Chinese New Year,
let's choose a good day
for you two
to get married.
What do you think?
Sure, Mom.
Nice!
That's settled, then.
Let's dig in!
Come on.
Here.
Ling Yi.
Happy Chinese New Year.
- What about me?
- Happy Chinese New Year.
Happy Chinese New Year.
Who's there?
Me.
What brings you here?
It's Happy Chinese New Year,
a time of reunion.
I thought you'd be celebrating
with Fang Muyang.
I told him I'd be in Jiangnan.
Wouldn't your parents be upset
if you're not celebrating at home?
I am celebrating at home.
When are you planning to have kids?
What?
Drop that act.
When are you planning to have kids?
Since you're with him now,
it'll come sooner or later.
Do you remember what I told you
when you got married?
Yeah, Mom.
Got it.
Fei Ting.
I want to watch too.
Be careful.
Another shot.
Take it easy, Dad.
You're a good drinker too.
I just don't blush easily.
I'm not as good as you.
Fang.
My son.
Now,
there's only two of us here.
As the saying goes,
after wine comes the truth.
So,
let me ask you something.
Can you guarantee
that you'd be nice
to my daughter in this life?
Yes.
Of course.
♪After the laughter, I think of you♪
Dad.
♪After the storm, I think of you♪
I know
you're worried that Fei Ni would suffer
after marrying me.
I can't provide her
with much material wants,
but I can
promise you and Mom something.
I will always respect her,
love her
and support her.
♪When summer comes, I think of you♪
I won't let her regret choosing me.
♪The fallen leaves in autumn,
you belong to me♪
Come on.
Let us drink our hearts out.
Until we achieve our ambitions.
We'll make it big in the future.
♪There's a small place♪
♪Where everyone has big dreams♪
♪Every cute face♪
♪Glows from the heart♪
♪Even when we collide,
we hold our course♪
♪Even when we stumble,
we keep our resolve♪
♪You belong to me, you see the light♪
♪Remember, that's me thinking of you♪
Didn't you bring more clothes?
No.
This is warm enough.
Bundle up
when we go out.
It's cold outside.
Where are we going?
It's Chinese New Year.
Of course we're visiting family.
Have some tea.
Mujing.
I thought you're
celebrating in Jiangnan.
What brings you here?
I...
That was our plan.
But she was busy,
so I came instead.
How long will you be here?
Four days.
I switched shifts with my colleagues
so I could spend more time
with your sister.
Why don't you stay for lunch?
- Sure.
- No need.
How about this?
I'll cook something.
Your sister has never
tried my cooking too.
You can cook?
Where's the kitchen?
I'll take you there.
I'll be your assistant.
Sure.
We're cooking today.
Just sit here and wait.
Mujing.
Enjoy.
The factory
called me over.
I need to go.
You can have lunch with Dad and Mom.
Don't wait for me.
You're going out again?
You promised to visit my family today.
I know. I'll be back.
Don't worry, I'll be back
right after I'm done.
Bye.
Not bad, Qu Hua.
Your knife skills are just as good
as your scalpel skills.
Nice.
I learned cooking when I was a student.
I didn't expect it
to be useful today.
How are things between you
and my sister?
Pretty good.
Really?
Yes.
Some marriages are like candies.
Sweet,
but too much sugar
can be bad for health.
Some marriages are like Chinese herbs.
Bitter,
but in the long term,
it improves your health.
You'd better check on me later.
I've been having a lot of candies.
Why don't you tell me
stories about your sister?
I want to know her better.
Sure.
Don't tell her I told you, though.
My sister
has always been proud.
She can be stubborn, too.
There was this time
when she scored
99.5 marks in a test.
When she reached home, she cried.
I think she was
utterly defeated by that 0.5 marks.
I got 59 marks.
Brother Fei Ting, you're here.
Yeah.
Brother Fei Ting, are you cold?
Cold?
No.
My brother is having an affair?
No way.
Lin Mei, this must be
a misunderstanding.
I saw him entering someone's house,
and someone called him Brother Fei Ting.
Besides, his shirt often
reeks of snow cream.
He kept lying that he has
work in the factory.
What else could it be, if not an affair?
Don't get worked up.
My brother's not that kind of person.
Let's go and see.
Here.
Wait.
If your brother is having an affair,
what should I...
Don't worry.
I'll be on your side.
Someone's knocking.
Brother Fei Ting, I'll get the door.
See?
Who are you looking for?
Fei Ting is my brother,
not yours.
(Happiness)
Here comes the fish!
Brother Fei Ting!
Here are the potatoes!
Hand them over.
Serve the beef.
Sure.
Fei Ni?
Hey, Fei Ting.
Your sister's here.
Quick!
Coming!
What brings you two here?
Wait...
What are you doing here?
I...
It's...
It's Chinese New Year.
Lots of parties around,
so I'm helping Mr. Li cooking.
So, when you said you've got work,
you've been cooking too?
Yeah.
It's getting cold lately,
so I'm saving up to buy you a sweater.
You've been wanting one, too.
Why are you here, though?
To visit you.
Fang Muyang is waiting for me.
I'm going home.
Stay safe.
How did you know
I'm here?
What if the factory knows you're here?
You might lose your job.
No.
They're a strict bunch,
but as long as it doesn't
affect production,
they'll just turn a blind eye.
Besides,
Mr. Li is paying me 3.50 yuan for this.
Think about it.
If I help out three times a month,
I get paid more than 10 yuan.
Don't keep this from me again.
You're bad
at hiding secrets.
Yeah.
I know.
Another thing.
Make sure this doesn't affect your work.
Let's go.
To my parents' house.
No.
They're waiting for me inside.
Brother Fei Ting.
They're rushing.
Call him Comrade Fei Ting!
Yes.
Comrade Fei Ting.
They're rushing.
Coming.
You let her call you Brother?
Be serious when you're working.
Don't smile.
Come back.
Bye.
Stay safe.
Meat!
Meat with celery!
Look who's got an appetite.
Of course we're having meat
in Chinese New Year.
Ever since Aunt Mei moved out,
we haven't had meat often.
Before your aunt got married,
she brought her meat and
textile coupons back home
for our family to use.
Now that she's married,
she's giving those vouchers
to someone else's family.
Hush.
That's why they say
a married daughter
is like water thrown outside the door.
There's no use being nice to her.
Eat up.
But you know what else water is?
Water symbolizes wealth.
Darling, we've been getting richer
ever since you married
into our family, see?
- That's more like it.
- Have some meat, darling.
No, it's for our son.
Grandma.
Why is there so little meat?
You call this little?
It's underneath the veggies.
You can have it all, here.
No one else can have meat today.
It's all mine!
We're family. It's for everyone.
Mom, have some meat.
Have more.
Here you go.
Thank you.
Mom.
Hey, everyone.
You're here, Lin Mei.
I'm here to wish you a happy new year.
The cooperative gave us some
canned food before the holidays.
I kept two for myself.
The rest is for you.
Great.
You haven't had lunch?
No.
Perfect timing. Join us.
Where's Dad?
He's working overtime.
Come here.
Let your aunt sit here.
Let me get you some rice.
Thanks, Mom.
Jianshe, have you been good?
Yes.
Jianshe.
Your aunt picked a good time
to come back.
She rarely comes back.
Now that we're having meat today,
she's back.
Aunt, don't take my meat.
I won't.
You can have meat at my house.
Your aunt
and her husband are both working.
She's probably got
unlimited meat coupons.
Unlike us.
We need to scrimp and save,
and still entertain an uninvited guest.
Aihong, don't say that.
She's family, not an uninvited guest.
It's not a big deal.
Lin Mei, dig in.
Here.
Dig in.
Eat up.
Try the tofu.
Lin Mei.
Your nephew is a growing boy.
Why take his food?
I'm not.
There's still plenty left.
No, there's only like
100 grams of meat in here.
In the past, I gave this family
all my meat coupons.
That's worth a few kilograms of meat.
Now that I'm married,
I can't even eat at home in peace?
What?
Have I been feeding
a bunch of ingrates all along?
Lin Mei.
You used to be part of the Lins.
It's normal for you to give us
your meat coupons.
Now that you've married into the Feis,
you shouldn't even
come back here for lunch.
Don't you know that?
Exactly.
Happy new year!
Mom.
- Fei Ting, you're here.
- Song.
Aihong, Jianshe.
Happy Chinese New Year.
Lin Mei.
I got these...
You bought these
from the restaurant, right?
Hand them over.
Had you come any later,
I'd have been kicked out by now.
Look.
Fei Ting.
Sit down and join us.
Dig in.
Here.
Come here, Jianshe.
Let's have meat together.
Let's have meat.
Take whatever you want.
What shall we have?
Meat.
Here.
Give me that.
You should eat, too.
Aihong.
I'm not freeloading.
I asked Fei Ting
to buy some food from the restaurant.
I wonder if the Lins
can eat something
brought over by the Feis.
Aunt.
I'm part of the Fei family now.
How are you part of the Fei family?
My aunt is,
so I am too.
Dad, Mom.
Call me Fei Jianshe from now on.
I...
You glutton.
Eat up.
Have more meat.
So much meat.
Enjoy.
Have some fish.
Here.
Fish and meat.
I'll pick the bones out.
Eat this.
Here, Fei Ting.
Have some meat.
Thank you.
What happened to your blanket?
I spilled some water
on the blanket,
so it's wet.
How are you going to keep yourself
warm tonight?
It's okay.
Go to sleep.
It's not going to dry tonight.
Well...
Okay.
Sleep tight.
Are you okay?
I'm fine.
Go to sleep. I'm not cold.
That's enough.
You can share my blanket.
You don't want to catch a cold.
Here.
Thanks.
Go to sleep.
Fang Muyang, what are you doing?
What are you...
You're so annoying!
You're pulling my hair!
♪After the laughter, I think of you♪
♪After the storm, I think of you♪
♪In the little courtyard,
there you are dancing♪
♪That earnest you,
smiling so innocently♪
♪In spring, I stay by your side♪
♪When summer comes, I watch over you♪
♪In the light of dawn, you belong to me♪
♪At the edge of the world,
I will still hold you tight♪
♪There is a small place♪
♪Where they carry big dreams♪
♪Every lovely face♪
♪Shines brightly in the heart♪
♪Even when we collide,
we hold our course♪
♪Even when we stumble,
we keep our resolve♪
♪My you, walking toward the distance♪
♪Please carry our dreams
and let them soar♪